<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inwardinvestment Content Marketing on Mentoring for the digitally crippled</title>
    <link>https://fb.postpal.com/tags/inwardinvestment-content-marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inwardinvestment Content Marketing on Mentoring for the digitally crippled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 16:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fb.postpal.com/tags/inwardinvestment-content-marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Key Insights from 3 Years of Inward Investment Marketing...</title>
      <link>https://fb.postpal.com/pick/me/for/king</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fb.postpal.com/pick/me/for/king</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align:
center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a
href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QczdWGuzacE/VV2zrjMo-JI/AAAAAAAAGF0/NAZ7W5L0wTo/s1600/3%2BYears%2BInsights.png&#34;
imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img
border=&#34;0&#34;
src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QczdWGuzacE/VV2zrjMo-JI/AAAAAAAAGF0/NAZ7W5L0wTo/s640/3%2BYears%2BInsights.png&#34;
/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been
three fascinating years since we established Clarity specifically to focus on
Inward Investment Marketing. So what have we learned during that time? And what
insights can we offer about Inward Investment Marketing in 2015?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a
name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Here are three key insights from our three years
specialising in Inward Investment Marketing:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;1.
&amp;lsquo;Solutions Marketing&amp;rsquo; is the Way Forward&lt;/h3&gt;Over the last few years, many
leading businesses have invested in blogs that aim to &amp;lsquo;inform&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;solve
customers&amp;rsquo; problems&amp;rsquo; rather than &amp;lsquo;sell&amp;rsquo; in the traditional way. It&amp;rsquo;s an
effective approach because it focuses on the needs of the customer, builds trust
and highlights expertise as a basis for winning sales. Exemplary
&amp;lsquo;business-to-business&amp;rsquo; blogs include&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
href=&#34;https://forums.cat.com/t5/BLOG-On-The-Level/bg-p/CT_Blog&#34;&gt;Caterpillar&lt;/a&gt;
(construction equipment) and &lt;a
href=&#34;http://blog.jll.eu/research/&#34;&gt;JLL&lt;/a&gt; (property).&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve found that inward investment agencies
&lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; host and deliver excellent, solutions-focused blogs that
address the &amp;lsquo;location choice drivers&amp;rsquo; of expanding businesses, especially when
they team up with expert guest contributors from regional partner organisations
and companies. The benefits include building the region&amp;rsquo;s online profile
significantly (working with partners creates&lt;i&gt; scale&lt;/i&gt; and
&lt;i&gt;more informative content&lt;/i&gt;) and nurturing strong, on-going
relationships with expanding businesses. We think more investment agencies and
regional partnerships should seriously consider this approach.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2. It&amp;rsquo;s All About the Data (and How it&amp;rsquo;s
Presented)&lt;b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;More than ever before, &lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.clarity-strategies.com/2014/10/commercial-property-marketing-its-time.html&#34;&gt;businesses
make investment decisions on the basis of reliable data&lt;/a&gt; - most
obviously relating to costs - so communicating location data &lt;i&gt;clearly
and accessibly&lt;/i&gt; should be at the heart of effective Inward Investment
Marketing. That&amp;rsquo;s the rationale behind the ever-growing popularity of
&lt;i&gt;infographics &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;data visualisation.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unfortunately, most of the &amp;lsquo;infographics&amp;rsquo; we see fail to
communicate the data (i.e. the &lt;i&gt;numbers&lt;/i&gt;) clearly, or state
where the data came from, thereby being of little or no use to expanding
businesses. Inward investment marketers should therefore &lt;i&gt;be wary of the
attractive but useless infographic&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the
other hand, well implemented (i.e. accurate, clear, source-referenced)
infographics can enable investment agencies to communicate powerful location
data in a highly effective way. As a business, we&amp;rsquo;re increasingly focused on
developing interactive infographics driven by live data feeds (i.e.
database-linked). The objective has to be more informative and valuable inward
investment marketing content that communicates reliable location data in a way
that&amp;rsquo;s easy to consume, easy to update &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; great to look at
at the same time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;3. Inward Investment
Marketers Need to Keep Moving with the Times&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;The world of marketing
has moved extremely quickly over the last three years, sometimes making it
difficult to keep up. What&amp;rsquo;s certain is that the internet has driven the biggest
changes, and that inward investment marketers need to keep moving with the
times.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To cite just a couple of examples:&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Online Content Marketing (blogging)
requires a new kind of &lt;i&gt;solutions-driven&lt;/i&gt; content - it&amp;rsquo;s not
enough just to post old-style &lt;i&gt;news&lt;/i&gt; press releases (written
for &lt;i&gt;editors&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;readers&lt;/i&gt;) to your
blog.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Social media is now a serious marketing tool, as
increasing numbers of business decision makers engage on platforms such as
LinkedIn. Inward investment marketers need to get
social.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;In Summary&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;The priorities
for inward investment marketers in 2015 should be to move from traditional
&amp;lsquo;sales&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;PR&amp;rsquo; messages to location &amp;lsquo;solutions marketing&amp;rsquo;, underpinned by a
higher quality of data that investors can &lt;i&gt;confidently&lt;/i&gt;
incorporate into location evaluations. And they need to project these more
robust messages to prospective investors and intermediaries via up-to-date,
online channels and networks. Agencies that do these things will be in a
position to inform and influence business location decisions more than ever
before, thereby delivering real added value for their locations.&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We could go on, but &amp;lsquo;Four Key Insights for Three Years&amp;rsquo;
wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have worked so well. So all that&amp;rsquo;s left for us to say is
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thank You&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; to all the clients and
collaborators we&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of working with since 2012.&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Nick
Smillie&lt;br /&gt;MD, Clarity Business Strategies Ltd.&lt;br /&gt;21/5/15&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>