<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing Strategies on Mentoring for the digitally crippled</title>
    <link>https://fb.postpal.com/tags/marketing-strategies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marketing Strategies on Mentoring for the digitally crippled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fb.postpal.com/tags/marketing-strategies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>B2B and Industrial Marketing: Why is Social Media Confusing Us? </title>
      <link>https://fb.postpal.com/post/socialmedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fb.postpal.com/post/socialmedia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34;
class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;
text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:
center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a
href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cfXd1Qhrs4Q/UJe8wxufPmI/AAAAAAAAAl0/LnyORYT62Kc/s1600/confused.jpg&#34;
imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img
border=&#34;0&#34;
src=&#34;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cfXd1Qhrs4Q/UJe8wxufPmI/AAAAAAAAAl0/LnyORYT62Kc/s800/confused.jpg&#34;
/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34;
style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s Confused by Social Media.
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here are some
interesting findings regarding industrial companies and social media marketing
from GlobalSpec’s recent survey: &lt;a
href=&#34;http://beta.globalspec.com/advertising/trends-wp/2012_Marketing_Trends_WP&#34;&gt;Trends
in Industrial Marketing 2012&lt;/a&gt;: How Manufacturers are Marketing
Today:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;57% of industrial companies now use social media
applications&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;37% of them are spending more on social media
activities in 2012 than in 2011&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;b&gt;But…&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Only 17% of them are happy with their social
media efforts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The conclusions to draw
from these findings are pretty obvious: most industrial companies have taken the
decision to embrace social media marketing, but when it comes to implementation
and getting results, they’re confused and disappointed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;b&gt;So, what seems to be the problem?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;The social media phenomenon is massive and fast-moving, so there is, no
doubt, a whole gamut of reasons why B2B and industrial marketers are fazed by
it. But I’ve got a strong suspicion of what lies at the heart of the problem -
the very real, but not always clearly defined or understood, differences between
‘consumer’ and &amp;lsquo;B2B&amp;rsquo; (business-to-business) marketing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;b&gt;How are consumer marketers using social media?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Think about the social media-focused campaigns that hit the
headlines – the car manufacturer’s orange ‘&lt;a
href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AzG4afr9yBI&amp;amp;feature=related&#34;&gt;spokespuppet&lt;/a&gt;’,
for example, or the chocolate company’s ‘&lt;a
href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TVblWq3tDwY&#34;&gt;eyebrow dance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;.
I suspect that many of my B2B marketing colleagues would share the sentiments of
the thought leader who posted this comment on YouTube:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;What the hell does
this s**t have to do with chocolate?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;What the hell indeed. The fact is that consumer marketers (companies
selling goods like cars and chocolate to individual consumers) are using social
media forums like Facebook in ways that often don’t make immediate sense to B2B
and industrial marketers. They’re engaging in online conversations with their
customers that often seem (or perhaps are) trivial, have no
&lt;i&gt;obvious&lt;/i&gt; goals and have no direct connection to the act of
purchasing the company’s product (e.g. no link to a website where the product
can actually be bought). And we, the B2B crowd, are looking at it all and
thinking: there’s something new and important going on here, but I don’t know
what it is, or how it&amp;rsquo;s relevant to me promoting my light engineering
business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;So why are consumer marketers doing it
like that?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well, our groovy consumer marketing
peers are doing something that would never cross the minds of most B2B and
industrial marketers. The primary objective of their social media activities is
to nurture positive &lt;i&gt;feelings&lt;/i&gt; towards their brands at an
&lt;i&gt;emotional&lt;/i&gt; rather than rational level - to make consumers feel
a &lt;i&gt;connection&lt;/i&gt; with their brand. By uploading your dancing
eyebrows clip, you’ll feel an &lt;i&gt;affinity&lt;/i&gt; with the chocolatier;
by filming your dog lip-synching to Lady Gaga, you’re
&lt;i&gt;engaging&lt;/i&gt; personally with the broadband supplier.&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It’s all based on the fact that our buying decisions as
consumers are strongly influenced by our feelings towards
&lt;b&gt;brands&lt;/b&gt; – much more than rational cost-benefit analyses. We
buy into the whole world of Apple products because we embrace everything that is
‘Apple’ – from its design ethos to the fact that it’s not Microsoft – not
because, say, we get more processing power per pound spent. And many consumers,
clearly, are prepared to spend their time engaging with social media campaigns
that are carefully conceived to develop the sense of affinity between themselves
and their favourite brands.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;But is this approach
applicable to B2B and Industrial Marketing?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;Let’s think this one through. The ‘brand affinity’ approach to consumer
social media marketing is based on an understanding of how
&lt;i&gt;consumers&lt;/i&gt; make buying decisions. For example:&lt;br
/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consumer buying decisions are often
primarily emotional, not rational (e.g. your new
car)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consumers often buy stuff primarily for pleasure, not
utility&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consumers are usually only accountable to themselves
(or at most, to their partners or parents)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consumers often
associate brands with their individual identities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consumers
won’t lose their jobs for making duff buying
decisions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, I’m not going to argue that
corporate buyers are automatons, uninfluenced by emotion or the power of brands.
However, I will argue that corporate buying is fundamentally different from
consumer buying, in that it’s primarily rational and utilitarian, and because
corporate buyers are responsible to shareholders. They could lose their jobs if
their buying decisions aren’t sound.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All of which leads
me to the conclusion that &lt;b&gt;corporate buyers need &lt;i&gt;solutions
&lt;/i&gt;to their essentially practical procurement
&lt;i&gt;problems&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;. They need products that are longer
lasting, cheaper, easier to use, lower maintenance, faster, and so on – they
need to maximise ROI. But guess what? You knew that already. Providing solutions
to your customers’ problems is what you’ve always done, and what has made your
company successful. A change in the media environment, from printed materials to
the internet, doesn’t change that fundamental fact. It does, however, open up a
whole range of new ways of communicating your solutions to your prospective
customers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;How B2B and industrial companies can
use social media to solve their customers’ problems&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;I’ll keep this bit simple. Why not just do it like this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br
/&gt;1. Identify your customers’ problems, and how your products and services
provide the solutions they need&lt;br /&gt;2. Make those solutions the focus of
your website, both in terms of static page content and a regularly updated blog
(read more about &lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.clarity-strategies.com/2012/07/engineers-why-your-company-should-start.html#more&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;technical
blogging&amp;rsquo;&amp;nbsp;here&lt;/a&gt;). This will help you get found on search
engines, and make your prospective customers want to engage with you (read more
about &lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.clarity-strategies.com/2012/09/industrial-company-websites-its-time.html#more&#34;&gt;improving
your website&amp;nbsp;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;3. Post your
&lt;i&gt;solution-rich&lt;/i&gt; articles to your company social media pages
(e.g. LinkedIn, Twitter and Google+) so that prospective buyers in need of your
solutions can follow you there (and you can find out who they are).&lt;br
/&gt;4. Optimise your website with &amp;lsquo;calls-to-action&amp;rsquo;, so that your prospective
customers can subscribe to receive your solutions by e-mail (and you can find
out who they are)&lt;br /&gt;5. Think about where your prospective customers go
online in search of solutions (e.g. LinkedIn industry discussion groups) and
post your articles there too&lt;br /&gt;6. Remember that your customers want
solutions to their problems not sales pitches. Therefore give them ’10 ways to
cut the costs of machining titanium’, rather than ‘buy our new miracle cutting
tool today!!!’&lt;br /&gt;7. Don’t waste your customers’ time with social media
tittle tattle. As you know, they’re corporate buyers, not teenagers following
the X Factor&lt;br /&gt;8. Talk about what’s of interest to your customers
(solutions to their problems), not what’s of interest to you (Geoff’s
retirement, your latest award, or the great work your company does for
charity)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And when your marketing company bangs on about
your ‘brand’ (because that’s what &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt; like to talk about)
remember that you’re probably not Caterpillar or Cadburys, and that they’ve
probably not completely nailed the differences between consumer and B2B
marketing. Your ‘brand’ is all about your ability to solve your customers’
problems. And that’s what you need to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>